

VISHNU AJITH

DATA ANALYST | WEB DEVELOPER

PROFILE:

Experienced Critical incident manager with a demonstrated history of working in the information technology and service industry.

Passionate in Web development and Data Analysis. Have a core strength in programming languages such as Python, Java, React, Javascipt, Django, Kotlin, Html & CSS. Keen to gain more knowledge about Artificial Intelligence and Data Science which would be a catalyst in the emerging techno world.

SKILLS:

- Python, Django
- Java, Javascript, React
- Mainframe (COBOL & JCL)
- Middleware (Tomcat & IIS)
- ITIL
- MySQL, MongoDB, Firebase
- HTML & CSS
- · Problem Solving

CONTACT INFORMATION:

Phone: +91 6238348375

Email: 27vishnu07@gmail.com Website: <u>ajithv-portfolio.web.app</u>

LinkedIn: @vishnuajith

WORK EXPERIENCE:

CRITICAL INCIDENT MANAGER

Infosys | 2020-Present

- Experience in managing the lifecycle of all unplanned interruptions, malfunctions, and quality reductions of provided IT services. Main goal is to follow incident management protocols and restore provided IT services to normal operation as quickly as possible. Skilled in ServiceNow tool.
- Have 1+ years of experience in Data Analysis using Python for Internal Auditing.

WEB DEVELOPER & DATA ANALYST

Freelancer | 2019-Present

- Designed and developed various web applications using React, Redux, Django, Firebase, HTML and CSS.
- Acquired knowledge in Data visualization, Tableau and Power BI.

EDUCATION

BACHELOR'S IN COMPUTER APPLICATION - (BCA)

St. Joseph's College, Devagiri | 2017-2020

• Completed my Bachelor's in Computer Application from St. Joseph's College, Devagiri, Calicut with an aggregate of 69.8%.

XII - ICSE

Auxilium Nava Jyoti (ICSE) School, Calicut | 2015-2017

 Completed my 12th from Auxilium Nava Jyoti (ICSE) School - (Computer Science) with an aggregate of 79.5%



INTERESTS:

- Data Science
- Artificial Intelligence
- · Big Data
- Web Development
- Data Analysis
- Problem Solving
- Sports

OTHERS:

 Basketballer - (KBA - Kerala Basketball Association member)

CERTIFICATIONS:

- IBM Certified in Python 101 for Data Science
- Google Certified in Google Analytics for Beginners
- <u>Google Certified in Google Developers -</u> <u>Introduction to Kotlin</u>
- Hacker Rank Certified in Python
- <u>Simplilearn Certified in Big Data Tools for</u>
 <u>Beginners</u>
- Cognitive Class Certified in Introduction to
 Data Science
- Infosys Certified Kanban Practitioner
- RedTeam Hacker Academy Introduction to Cyber Security and Ethical Hacking

PROJECTS:

- <u>COVID-TRACKER</u> Intended to provide information about recent covid trends.
- BOT Created a telegram bot to check the Covid-19 vaccine slot availability.
- Quote Generator Random Quote Generator.
- SNow API fetch using Python.
- Portfolio Website

DECLARATION:

I solemnly declare that all the above furnished information is free from error to the best of my knowledge and belief.